TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
yume ni yobare te… nami ni makare te…
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
fukai KAOSU no mori wo nuketara
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
kimi no kokoro de nanika ga kawaru
gin'iro no yoake ga ima
nagai nemuri wo uchikudaku you ni
Concept Design
3D Collaboration
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Digital Zero
Kawami Takuya
kimi no inochi ni PARUSU wo okuru
hitasura ni ikiru tame ni
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
kimi no hitomi no naka umareta bakarino
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
yume no kakera wo tsuyosa ni kaete yuke
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
jidai ni tobikomu yuuki no DIVER
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Sawa Reiko
Nomura Hiroshi
ima no kurushimi ya namida wo
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
afureru chikara douka shinjite
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
kagayaku tame ni tabitate SOLDIER
Production
소멸해라!
Disappear!
Musnahkan!
소멸해라! 매지컬 게이트!
Disappear, Magical Gate!
Musnahkan! Musnahkan Magical Gate!
글라디온! 그렇게나 이 데리트로스님을 방해하고 싶었나...
Gladion! You really wanted to hinder my plans...
Gladion! Lagi-lagi kau menghalangi Yang Mulia Deletloss ini...
그럼 슬슬 나도 게임에 참여해 볼까.
Then let me participate in the game as well.
Kalau begitu, akupun akan turut dalam permainan ini.
우선 한번 보여주어 보아라.
First, show it to me.
Sekarang, perlihatkan padaku.
네가 선택한 인간 웹다이버의 힘을 보여주어라!
Demonstrate the power of the Webdiver you chose!
Tunjukkan kekuatan Webdiver yang kau pilih itu!
데
De
데리
Dele
데리트
Delet
데리트로
Deletlo
데리트로스
Deletlos
데리트로스!
Deletloss!
데리트로스! 사
Deletloss! Dis
Deletloss! Hi
데리트로스! 사라
Deletloss! Disapp
Deletloss! Hilan
데리트로스! 사라지
Deletloss! Disappear
Deletloss! Hilangn
데리트로스! 사라진
Deletloss! Disappeared
Deletloss! Hilangnya
데리트로스! 사라진 그
Deletloss! Disappeared G
Deletloss! Hilangnya G
데리트로스! 사라진 글
Deletloss! Disappeared Gl
Deletloss! Hilangnya Gl
데리트로스! 사라진 글라
Deletloss! Disappeared Gla
Deletloss! Hilangnya Gla
데리트로스! 사라진 글라디
Deletloss! Disappeared Glad
Deletloss! Hilangnya Glad
데리트로스! 사라진 글라디오
Deletloss! Disappeared Gladio
Deletloss! Hilangnya Gladio
데리트로스! 사라진 글라디온
Deletloss! Disappeared Gladion
Deletloss! Hilangnya Gladion
글라디온, 글라디온!
Hey, Gladion!
Gladion? Gladion!
뭔 일이야, 글라디온?
What's wrong, Gladion?
Kau kenapa, Gladion?
아, 아니야, 아무것도.
Uh, it's nothing, really.
Ah, aku tidak apa-apa.
기분 탓이었을 것이다. 그보다, 켄토.
That might be only my imagination... Leaving that aside, Kento.
Mungkin itu hanya perasaanku saja. Ada apa, Kento?
응, 오늘도 카이토를 보지는 못했어.
Yeah, I couldn't find Kaito again today.
Hari ini aku belum juga berhasil menemukan Kaito.
뭐, 슬슬 나 돌아갈게! 먼저 가자, 카론.
Well, it's time for me to go home! I'll be heading first, Karon.
Nah, sudah waktunya aku pulang. Aku duluan, ya, Karon.
그래. 주의하고, 켄토.
All right. Be careful, Kento.
Baiklah. Hati-hati, Kento.
어?
Huh?
Eh?
아, 아니야.
Er, it's nothing.
Ah, bukan apa-apa.
그럼 또 보자. 안녕!
See you again. Bye-bye!
Sampai nanti! Dah!
방금 전의 그 느낌은 뭘까.
I wonder what I felt a moment ago is.
Apa itu tadi?
악의 가득한 사악한 기운을.
Evil Aura full of evil intention.
Energi jahat yang kurasakan barusan...
켄토, 일어나!
Kento, it's the time already; wake up!
Kento, sudah siang! Ayo bangun!
응....
Okay.
Iya...
빨리 얼굴 씻어!
Go wash your face quickly!
Ayo cepat cuci mukamu!
알아!
I got it already!
Iya, aku tahu!
형! 서두르지 않으면 지각할 거야!
We're going to be late if you don't hurry, Kento!
Kakak, cepat! Nanti kita bisa terlambat!
알고 있어!
I know that!
Iya, sebentar!
어? 카이토?
Wha-? Kaito?
Hah? Kaito?
잘못 들었나.
Maybe that was someone else.
Yang benar saja.
형, 빨리!
Hurry up, Kento!
Ayo cepat, Kak!
카이토?!
Kaito?!
아빠! 엄마!
Mom! Dad!
Ayah! Ibu!
일어났구나, 켄토!
Good morning, Kento!
Pagi, Kento!
아침 다 먹고 가라.
You better eat your breakfast properly.
Sebelum sekolah, jangan lupa sarapan, ya.
그렇게 해, 형!
That's right, Kento!
Itu benar, Kak!
카이토.
Kaito.
Kaito...
왜, 형?
Why, Kento?
Ada apa, Kak?
카이토, 너, 정말 카이토냐?
Kaito, are you really Kaito?
Kaito, apa kamu benar-benar Kaito?
뭐라는 거야, 형?
What are you talking about, Kento?
Kakak ini bicara apa, sih?
카이토가 돌아왔어.
Kaito has came back.
Kaito sudah kembali.
카이토, 오늘 아침 어디 갔다 왔어?
Kaito, did you go somewhere this morning?
Kaito, memangnya tadi pagi kamu pergi kemana?
아니, 나 계속 집에 있었어.
No, I was at home all morning.
Tidak, aku di rumah terus, kok.
계속? 뭐라는 거야, 카이토! 너 없었지 않냐, 계속!
All morning? What the heck are you saying?! You weren't here all the time!
Lalu?! Kau ini bicara apa, Kaito?! Bukankah sudah lama kau menghilang?!
기억 안 나니?
Don't you remember?
Apa kau tidak ingat?
꿈꿨어, 켄토?
Are you still dreaming, Kento?
Kento, apa kau masih bermimpi?
꿈 아니야! 데리트로스가 침략해 와서 달아나던 너나 전세계의 아이들이 매지컬 게이트에 갇혔는데...
It's not a dream! You and the children all over the world were
Ini bukan mimpi! Deletloss melakukan invasi ke jaringan komputer,
running away from Deletloss but ended up being trapped in Magical Gate...
dan anak-anak di seluruh dunia yang terlambat melarikan diri terperangkap dalam Magical Gate...
그렇게나 무서운 꿈을 꿨구나?
You had such a scary dream, huh?
Wah, kamu habis mimpi buruk, ya?
꿈 아니라니까!
That is not a dream!
Ini bukan mimpi!
뭐야, 이 데리 어쩌고 하는 놈은.
What is Dele-whatever anyway?
Siapa itu yang bernama Dele... apakah itu?
그런 놈이 오면 아빠가 너희들을 지켜줄게!
If such rascal come to get you, Dad and the others will protect you kids!
Biarpun muncul seperti dia, Ayah pasti akan melindungi kalian!
아빠 멋져!
My dad is awesome!
Ayah gagah sekali!
카이토...
Kaito...
형은 말야, 이상해!
My brother's being weird!
Kakak ini aneh, deh!
자, 빨리 먹고 학교에 가라!
Come on, eat up and go to school!
Ayo, cepat habiskan makananmu dan berangkat ke sekolah!
그럼 나도 갈까?
Well, it's time for work!
Baiklah, sudah waktunya Ayah berangkat kerja!
그, 그런...
No way...
Ti-tidak mungkin...
뭐라는 거니. 카이토라면 어제도 그저께도 계속 집에 있었어.
What are you talking about? Kaito has always been home all the time.
Kau ini bicara apa? Dari kemarin-kemarin, Kaito terus ada di rumah.
만화 중독이구나! 도대체 인간의 의식을 인터넷 세계에 넣는다니 맙소사, 말도 안 돼.
You're too addicted to comics! Putting the consciousness of human into the network? Now that's crazy.
Kau terlalu banyak baca komik! Lagipula,
mana mungkin bisa mengirimkan kesadaran manusia ke dalam dunia jaringan?
아니야. 꿈이 아니야! 그래! 나 지금 침대에서 꿈꾸고 있나 봐.
No way. It wasn't a dream! Maybe I'm sleeping on my bed and still in my dream right now.
Tidak, ini bukan mimpi! Ah, aku tahu! Pasti saat ini aku sedang tidur dan bermimpi, ya.
그럼 여기는 꿈 속의 세계, 그 증거로 이런 짓을 해도 아프지 않을
Which means I'm in the world of dream and as the proof, doing this shouldn't hurt--
Artinya, ini adalah dunia mimpi, dan sebagai buktinya, dipukul sekeras apapun,
테니까... 아야!
then-- ouch...
pasti tidak sakit-- aduh, duh...
아프잖아! 그럼 꿈이 아니란 거네? 말도 안 돼!
It hurts! So it's not a dream at all! No way!
Kenapa sakit, ya? Berarti ini bukan mimpi! Tidak mungkin!
그래! 글라디온 컨트롤러!
Oh, yeah! Gladion Controller should be there!
Oh, iya! Gladion Controller!
없어?! 컨트롤러가 없어!
It isn't! The controller disappeared!
Tidak ada! Controller-nya tidak ada!
에? 플러그 잇 터미널도 없어!
What? Even the Plug It terminal isn't there!
Eh? Bahkan terminal Plug It-nya juga tidak ada!
카론, 뭔 일이야, 이건?
Karon, what's actually happening here?
Karon, apa yang sebenarnya terjadi?
카론, 야, 카론! 조용히만 있지 말고 뭐라고 좀 해봐!
Karon, hey, Karon! Stop being dumb and say something!
Karon? Oi, Karon! Jangan cuma diam! Ayo katakan!
형, 뭐해, 지각하려고 그래?
Hey, what're you doing, bro? You're gonna be late!
Kakak ini sedang apa, sih? Nanti terlambat, loh!
카이토...
Kaito...
카론은 아빠가 만든 미니 컴퓨터야. 말 못하잖아.
Karon is a mini robot made by dad. It definitely can't speak.
Karon, kan, robot mini buatan Ayah. Mana mungkin bisa bicara.
먼저 갈게!
I'm going first, then!
Aku duluan, ya!
기다려, 카이토!
Wait for me, Kaito!
Tunggu, Kaito!
말도 안돼!
I can't believe my eyes!
Ini mustahil!
나오키에욧!
Eetz mee, Naoki!
Akyuwh Naoki!
그런 개그 최고!
I love gags like that!
Lawakanmu lucu sekali!
아, 안녕, 켄토.
Ah, good morning, Kento.
Selamat pagi, Kento.
여!
Hey!
Hai!
쇼우도... 나오키도... 츠바사까지...
Shou... Naoki... even Tsubasa...
Shou... Naoki... dan juga Tsubasa...
아직 매지컬 게이트에 갇혀 있을 텐데.
They're supposed to be trapped in Magical Gate.
seharusnya masih terperangkap dalam Magical Gate.
뭔 일이라도 있어, 켄토?
Is there something wrong, Kento?
Ada apa denganmu, Kento?
아, 아니, 아무것도, 아무것도 아니야.
Uh, no, nothing, it's nothing serious.
Um, tidak, kok, bukan apa-apa.
대체 뭐가 어떻게 되고 있는 거야?
What the actual heck is going on?
Sebenarnya, apa yang terjadi, ya?
전혀 모르겠어.
Nothing makes any sense.
Aku tidak mengerti sama sekali.
켄토, 안녕!
Kento, good morning!
Selamat pagi, Kento!
글라디온?
Gladion?
응, 글라디온! 아오이는 알 거야.
Yeah, Gladion! You know about him, right?
Iya. Kamu tahu tentang Gladion, kan?
아오이네 할아버지가 만든 매지컬 게이트를 지키는 프로그램.
He's a program made by your grandfather to protect Magical Gate.
Dia adalah program yang dibuat oleh kakekmu untuk melindungi Magical Gate.
모르는데. 뭐 말이야?
I don't know that. What's this about?
Aku tidak tahu itu. Apa maksudmu?
뭐?! 뭐라는 거니? 글라디온 말이야!
Hey! Don't joke on me! How come you didn't know him?
Tidak mungkin! Kau ini bicara apa? Masa tidak tahu Gladion?
켄토...
Kento...
뭔 일이야, 켄토, 아오이.
What's going on, Kento, Aoi?
Ada apa, sih, Kento, Aoi?
모두 기억 안 나? 너희 모두를 구해준 정의의 웹나이트 말이야!
You guys do remember, right? About the Webknight of Justice that saved every one of you?
Kalian semua pasti juga ingat, kan? Tentang Webknight pembela kebenaran
yang telah menyelamatkan kalian semua?
뭐, 뭐야? 글라디온은.
I don't know about this Gladion thing.
Memangnya Gladion itu apa, sih?
그거 새로운 게임이야?
Is that a new game?
Itu judul game baru, ya?
어?
What?
Apa?
안녕, 얘들아!
Good morning, everyone!
Selamat pagi, anak-anak!
안녕하세요!
Good morning!
Selamat pagi, Pak!
오늘도 다 왔지?
I guess nobody's missing today?
Kalian masuk semuanya, kan?
감기가 유행하는 것 같으니 조심해라.
It seems cold is spreading widely lately, so please be careful.
Jaga kesehatan kalian karena sekarang sedang musim penyakit flu.
그리고 내일은 드디어 공작숙제 제출일이다. 모두 잊지 말도록!
And finally, tomorrow is the due for craft homework. Make sure you don't forget yours!
Dan besok adalah saatnya untuk mengumpulkan PR keterampilan. Jangan lupa, ya!
네.
Got it.
Iya.
이런 곳에 있었구나, 켄토.
So you've been in here, Kento?
Kento, ternyata kau di sini?
아오이.
Aoi.
찾았잖아. 학교 끝나고 같이 놀러가기로 약속했었는데. 모두 기다리고 있어.
I was searching for you, you know? You promised to go play together
Aku sudah mencarimu. Kau kan bilang sudah janji untuk pergi main sepulang sekolah. Yang lainnya sudah menunggu.
after the school. Everybody's waiting for you.
응.
Okay.
Baiklah.
왜 그래? 오늘 켄토 안색이 안 좋은데. 몸살 난 거 같아?
What's the matter? You don't look so good today. Are you sick?
Kenapa? Hari ini kau kelihatan lesu. Sedang tidak enak badan, kah?
사실은,
Well, the truth is...
Sebenarnya...
응, 그런 꿈을 꿨구나.
Ah, so you had that kind of dream.
Hm, jadi itu, ya, mimpimu.
꿈? 아니야, 그런 거!
Dream? No, I mean it!
Mimpi? Itu bukan mimpi!
꿈이야. 그러니까 그런 일이 일어나지 않고 모두가 있겠지!
It's definitely a dream. I mean, such thing didn't happen, and everybody's here!
Pasti mimpi. Buktinya, teman-teman yang lain ada semuanya.
그래도,
But...
Tapi...
그럼 켄토는 내가 거짓말한다고 생각하는 거야?
So Kento, you think I'm the lying one here?
Jadi, sekarang kau menganggap aku sedang berbohong. Begitu?
너무해. 난 모르는데... 글라디온이고 뭐고... 정말로...
That's just mean. I really don't know... about that Gladion... really...
Jahatnya. Padahal aku benar-benar tidak tahu tentang Gladion itu... sungguh...
그, 그래! 꿈이 맞아! 로봇과 합체해 나쁜 놈과 싸우는 건. 미안, 아오이! 내가 잘못 봤어.
Uh, you're right! Fighting against bad guy by combining with a robot--
Iya, iya, baiklah! Itu cuma mimpi, ya.
Mana mungkin aku bergabung dengan robot untuk bertarung dengan penjahat.
that's definitely a dream. Sorry, Aoi! Something's just wrong with me.
Maaf ya, Aoi! Sepertinya ada yang salah denganku.
알았으면 됐어.
It's okay if you know.
Baguslah kalau kau mengerti.
응.
Yeah.
Iya.
그럼 가자. 모두 기다려.
Then, let's go. Everybody's waiting.
Nah, ayo jalan. Semuanya sudah menunggumu.
어디에?
Go to where?
Kemana?
당연하잖아. 매지컬 게이트!
That's obvious. To Magical Gate!
Kemana lagi? Ya ke Magical Gate!
매지컬 게이트?
Magical Gate?
매지컬 게이트가 게임 센터야?!
By Magical Gate, you mean a game center?!
Magical Gate itu maksudnya nama game center?!
모두 기다렸구나!
Sorry for making you all wait!
Maaf sudah membuat kalian lama menunggu.
형은 느려!
You're late, Kento!
Kakak lama sekali!
카이토.
Kaito.
Kaito?
뭔 일이야, 켄토. 나하고의 백번승부에 늦다니 내가 무섭냐!
What the hell were you doing? Coming late to our match-- are you that afraid of me?
Dari mana saja kau, Kento? Sampai-sampai telat untuk seratus persaingan kita. Kau takut, ya?
뭐라고? 알았어! 승부다, 나오키!
What did you say? You asked for a match and there'll be one, Naoki!
Apa katamu?! Baiklah, akan kuladeni kau!
가자, 나오키!
Let's do this, Naoki!
Ayo kita mulai, Naoki!
이번에 이기면 40승 39패! 내가 앞서네!
If I win this one, it'll be 40:39! It's going to be my lead!
Kalau bisa memenangkan ini, maka aku akan unggul dengan skor 40 kemenangan dan 39 kekalahan.
힘내, 형!
Do your best, brother!
Ayo terus, Kak! Jangan takut!
갔다 왔어!
Thank you for the meal!
Mari makan!
있잖아, 오늘 학교에 수영장이 있었어. 그래서 작은 풀을 전부 헤엄쳤어!
So, today, there's a swimming lesson in school. And you know what? I can swim in all of the small ones!
Mau dengar, tidak? Hari ini di sekolah ada pelajaran renang.
Lalu, aku bisa berenang di semua kolam dangkal!
대단하지! 이거 맛있다.
Isn't it awesome?! This tastes good.
Hebat, kan?! Wah, makanannya enak sekali.
정말? 엄마는 요리책하고 싸워 이겼는데.
Really? I cooked it from a recipe book!
Benar? Itu makanan yang baru Ibu praktikkan dari buku resep!
뭘 하든, 도전은 필요하지.
Whatever the matter is, trying something new is important.
Dalam hal apapun, praktik itu sangat penting.
맞아, 아빠!
That's right, Dad!
Ayah benar sekali!
카이토, 이거 먹어.
Kaito, you can have this.
Kaito, ini, aku beri satu.
아, 고마워, 형!
Ah, thanks, bro!
Ah, terima kasih, Kak!
응!
No probs!
Sama-sama!
으악!
Argh!
Uwaa!
뭔 일이니, 켄토.
What's the matter, Kento?
Ada apa, Kento?
지, 지금 저기,
T-There's something just now...
Y-yang tadi itu...
젓가락을 내밀면 안돼.
Don't stick out your chopsticks like that.
Jangan menunjuk dengan sumpit seperti itu.
아, 미안.
Ah, sorry about that.
I-Iya, maaf.
이상한 녀석이네.
You're such a weird guy.
Kau ini aneh sekali.
이상한 형!
Weird brother!
Kakak memang aneh!
뭐, 꿈이어서 다행인 걸까. 모두 무사하고.
Well, I guess it's good that it's only a dream. Everyone's safe anyway.
Yah, tapi syukurlah kalau itu hanya mimpi. Apalagi semua baik-baik saja.
글라디온... 정말 너는 꿈이었던 거냐.
Gladion... were you only a dream, too?
Gladion... benar kamu cuma ada dalam mimpi?
켄토.
Kento.
글라디온?
Gladion?
카론.
Karon.
기분 탓이였을 거야.
That must be my imagination.
Pasti cuma perasaanku saja.
그래!
Alright then!
Baiklah!
공작 숙제나 해야지!
Time for the craft homework!
Saatnya untuk mengerjakan tugas keterampilan!
Brought to you by Subdiver
알게 되겠지. 컨트롤러를 다시 만들어 플러그잇하면 그게 꿈이었는지...
I'll know whether it was a dream after making the controller again and plugging it.
Dengan ini, aku akan tahu kalau aku membuat controller dan melakukan
plug it sekali lagi, aku bisa tahu apakah itu hanya mimpi, atau...
어떠냐, 나오키. 51승 49패. 내가 앞서네...
How's that, Naoki? 51:49. It's my lead...
Bagaimana, Naoki? Kali ini aku unggul dengan 51 kemenangan dan 49 kekalahan...
아, 꿈이었구나. 이제 고비네... 힘내자!
Oh, I fall asleep. Just a little bit more. I should do my best!
Aku ketiduran lagi, ya? Tinggal sedikit lagi. Aku harus berusaha!
뭐야, 카론이잖아. 놀래키지 마.
It was you, Karon! Don't scare me like that.
Ternyata Karon, toh! Jangan mengagetkan begitu.
아니야. 이건 내 세계가 아니야.
No. This is not my own world.
Bukan. Ternyata ini bukan duniaku.
뭐가 문제인가, 유우키 군!
What's the problem, Yuuki?
Bagaimana keadaannya, Taketo?
이전에 매지컬 소나가 고장 났던 원인을 모르겠습니다.
I can't find the cause of Magical Sonar's malfunction.
Penyebab kerusakan Magical Sonar masih belum diketahui.
매지컬 게이트에서 무언가가 일어나고 있다는 것은 틀림없는데.
But I'm sure that something is going on in Magical Gate.
Yang jelas, ini pasti dipengaruhi oleh sesuatu yang terjadi di Magical Gate.
어쨌든 복구를 서둘러라!
Anyway, hurry up with the recovery!
Pokoknya, perbaiki secepat mungkin!
네!
Got it!
Baik!
대체 매지컬 게이트에서 무슨 일이 일어나는 것인가.
What is actually happening inside Magical Gate...?
Apa yang sebenarnya terjadi di dalam Magical Gate?
안되나... 아니, 아닌 게 아니지. 그 때도 이랬어. 누군가가 날 부르는 목소리를 들었어.
It doesn't work... No, it hasn't. It was like this too at that time. I heard a voice of someone calling me.
Gagal, ya... Tidak. Masih belum gagal. Saat itu juga begini.
Aku mendengar suara seseorang yang memanggilku.
그래, 갑자기 머릿속에 떠올랐어.
Then, suddenly, I was inspired.
Setelah itu, tiba-tiba terbayang begitu saja di dalam otakku.
기관차로 변신하는 기사의 모습이.
Inspired of the image of a knight transforming into a train.
Wujud seorang kesatria yang berubah menjadi kereta api.
소리를 들었을 때, 나는 네 모습을 한 글라디온 컨트롤러를 만들고 있었어.
When I finally realized, I had already made a Gladion Controller that looks just like you.
Dan saat tersadar, tiba-tiba aku sudah membuat Gladion Controller yang berbentuk seperti dirimu.
켄토, 같이 공부할래?
Kento, wanna study with me?
Kento, ayo kita belajar bareng!
너는 계속 나를 부르고 있었어. 매지컬 게이트에서.
You were calling me all the time from Magical Gate, weren't you?
Kau terus berusaha memanggilku dari Magical Gate, ya?
켄토! 다음 승부다!
Kento! Time for the next match!
Kento! Saatnya kita bersaing!
나는 글라디온의 목소리를 들었어.
I did hear his voice.
Aku mendengar suaramu.
형, 서두르지 않으면 지각할 거야!
Kento, you're gonna be late if you don't hurry up!
Kakak, ayo cepat! Nanti terlambat, loh!
분명히 난 들었어. 글라디온의 목소리. 기억하고 있어. 아아, 기억하고 있어.
I definitely heard it. Gladion's voice. I remember. Yeah, I definitely do.
Tidak salah lagi. Aku memang mendengarnya. Aku masih ingat suara Gladion. Iya, aku masih ingat!
켄토... 켄토... 켄토...
Kento... Kento... Kento...
그 목소리, 꿈이 아니야.
That voice wasn't a dream.
Suara itu bukanlah mimpi.
나와 글라디온의 우정이 꿈일 리가 없어!
The friendship between Gladion and I cannot be a dream!
Persahabatanku dengan Gladion bukanlah mimpi!
켄토!
Kento!
꿈이 아니야.
It isn't a dream.
Ini bukan mimpi.
-켄토!
-형!
-Kento!
-Bro!
-Kakak!
여긴...
This is...
Di sini...
-켄토?
-켄토!
-Kento?
-Kento!
...다이버랜드가 절대 아니야!
...not Diverland!
...bukan Diverland!
젠장, 모두를 이용해 내 마음을 가지고 놀다니!
Damn, how dare he play with my feeling by using my friends!
Keterlaluan! Berani-beraninya dia menggunakan mereka untuk mempermainkan perasaanku.
용서 못 해, 용서할 것 같으냐, 데리트로스!
Unforgivable. I won't forgive you, Deletloss!
Tidak bisa diampuni. Aku tidak akan mengampunimu, Deletloss!
액세스 성공
Access Granted
Akses Berhasil
켄토, 글라디온 컨트롤러의 스위치를 눌러!
Kento, push the controller's button!
Kento, tekan tombol controller-nya!
글라디온!
Gladion!
그렇게 하면 거기서 탈출할 수 있어!
That way, you can escape from there!
Dengan begitu, kau bisa lolos dari sana!
좋아!
Alright!
Baiklah!
할아버지!
Grandpa!
Kakek!
오, 매지컬 소나가 복구되기 시작했구나!
Oh, Magical Sonar has begun to recover!
Oh, Magical Sonar berfungsi kembali!
역시 여기는 매지컬 게이트.
As expected, I am still in Magical Gate.
Ternyata ini memang Magical Gate.
글라디온!
Gladion!
모두!
Everyone!
Semuanya!
괜찮아, 켄토?
Are you okay, Kento?
Kau baik-baik saja, kan, Kento?
응. 근데 이건 대체...
Yes, but what is this all about...?
Iya, tapi, apa yang sebenarnya terjadi...?
데리트로스의 짓이다.
This is Deletloss' doing.
Ini adalah ulah Deletloss.
역시 그랬구나.
I knew it.
Benar dugaanku.
놈은 매지컬 게이트에서 다이버랜드로 돌아가는 길에 켄토를 붙잡아
He caught you while you were on your way back from Magical Gate to Diverland
Dia menangkapmu yang sedang dalam perjalanan pulang dari Magical Gate ke Diverland
매지컬 게이트 안에 만든 가짜 다이버랜드에 반송했어.
and returned you to a fake Diverland made inside Magical Gate.
dan mengurungmu dalam Diverland palsu yang dibuatnya di dalam Magical Gate.
근데, 데리트로스는 왜 나를...
But, why would Deletloss do that me...?
Tapi, kenapa Deletloss melakukan itu padaku...?
그건 웹다이버라는 것에 흥미가 있었기 때문이다.
That's because I was interested in Webdivers.
Itu karena aku menaruh minat padamu sebagai Webdiver.
지금의 목소리. 설마!
This voice. Don't tell me!
Suara itu. Jangan-jangan!
데리트로스다!
Deletloss!
켄토! 웹다이브해라!
Kento! Webdive now!
Kento! Lakukan Webdive!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
저건...
That's...
I-Itu...
왔군, 데리트로스.
You finally came, Deletloss.
Akhirnya kau muncul, Deletloss.
데리트로스?
Deletloss?
설, 설마.
N-no way.
T-tidak mungkin.
있을 수 없어!
That's not possible!
Ini mustahil!
이렇게 큰 프로그램이 매지컬 게이트에 존재하는 건... 분명히 여유 공간을 초과했을 텐데 이건 대체...
It's surprising that a program this big exists in Magical Gate. Its size must be exceeding the capacity.
Bisa-bisanya program sebesar itu ada di dalam Magical Gate. Ukurannya jauh melebihi kapasitas.
글라디온, 재규어온, 샤크온, 그리피온, 피닉스온.
Gladion, Jaguaron, Sharkon, Griffion, Phoenixon.
데리트로스, 접근합니다!
Deletloss is approaching to them!
Deletloss sedang mendekati mereka!
힘내, 켄토!
Hang in there, Kento!
Berjuanglah, Kento!
잘도 내가 만든 게임을 깼군. 우선은 칭찬하도록 하지. 다만 네놈은 실망스럽군!
Good job clearing the game I made. Let me praise you for that. But, you disappointed me!
Aku memuji kehebatanmu yang bisa menyelesaikan permainan yang kubuat untukmu.
Tapi, aku kecewa padamu.
웹다이버가 어떤가 했더니 결국은 평범한 인간에 지나지 않는군.
I always wondered how strong a Webdiver would be; turns out it's nothing more than a mere human.
Tadinya aku pikir sehebat apa Webdiver itu; ternyata hanya seorang manusia biasa.
아무리 보아도 네놈은 단순한 세포덩어리에 지나지 않는군. 그런 것이 프로그램을 넘는 힘을 가질 리가 없다!
No matter how much I examined, you're nothing more than a blob of cells.
Biar diperiksa seperti apapun, tetap saja kau tidak lebih dari sekumpulan sel!
Such thing wouldn't have a power that exceeds a program!
Benda seperti itu tidak mungkin memiliki kekuatan yang melebihi sebuah program!
하물며 영원한 존재, 이 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨리는 것 따위를 상상한다는 것은 멍청함의 극치이다!
Especially thinking to defeat me, an eternal being, is an ultimate stupidity!
Apalagi, untuk mengalahkan Deletloss yang abadi ini. Benar-benar tidak tahu diri!
역시 그런가. 넌 이해하지 않는 것인가. 인간의 마음, 마음에 담긴 용기와 우정. 무한의 힘을!
So I see. You won't be able to understand.
Ternyata benar. Kau tidak bisa memahaminya.
The humans' feeling; the bravery and friendship stored in their heart. The unlimited power!
Perasaan manusia; keberanian dan persahabatan yang tersimpan dalam hati mereka.
Kekuatan yang tidak ada batasnya!
나는 널 쓰러뜨릴 거야! 그리고 구할 거야! 매지컬 게이트에 갇힌 모두를!
I will take you down, and save everyone trapped inside Magical Gate!
Aku pasti akan mengalahkanmu dan menyelamatkan anak-anak yang terperangkap di Magical Gate!
그렇다면 무한의 힘을 여기에서 보여라! 웹다이버여!
Then, show me the so-called unlimited power, Webdiver!
Kalau begitu, tunjukkan kekuatan yang tidak ada batasnya itu, Webdiver!
뭐야, 이거? 방금 공격당한 거야?
What was that? Were we being attacked?
Yang tadi itu apa? Apa dia menyerang?
아니다. 눈을 떴을 뿐이다.
No. It merely opened its eyes.
Tidak. Itu hanya tatapan matanya saja.
눈을 떴다고?
Opened its eyes?
Tatapan mata?
녀석의 시선만으로 나오는 충격파의 위력이 이렇다는 것이다.
It means just by gazing, he could emit such a powerful shock wave like that.
Tatapan matanya saja memiliki kekuatan serangan yang begitu hebat.
우리와는 크기도 힘도 현저히 차이난다!
Both his scale and power differ greatly from us!
Baik ukuran maupun kekuatannya benar-benar berbeda dari kita!
어떡하지, 글라디온?
What should we do, Gladion?
Bagaimana ini, Gladion?
흩어져라! 뭉치면 당한다!
Spread out! If we're gathered like this, we'll get beaten!
Berpencarlah! Jika kita berkumpul, kita bisa kena serang!
그란발칸!
Granvulcan!
안돼! 모두 한 곳을 집중 공격해! 저 곳, 녀석의 중심점을!
Attacking like that won't do! Concentrate your attack at one point: its center!
Kalau sendiri-sendiri tidak akan bisa! Satukan semua serangan kalian di satu titik, yaitu pusat matanya!
알았다!
Got it!
Baik!
그런 손으로 이 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨릴 생각을 하다니, 까불지 마라!
You think you can take me down with these kind of attacks? Don't be kidding!
Kalian pikir bisa mengalahkan Deletloss dengan cara seperti ini? Jangan main-main!
데리트로스의 강력한 신호 감지! 글라디온 외의 자기보호 프로그램, 데미지 한계!
Strong signal from Deletloss detected! All programs except Gladion are at its damage limit!
Sinyal kuat dari Deletloss terdeteksi! Semua program kecuali Gladion mengalami kerusakan parah!
만약 또 공격을 받으면 붕괴될 겁니다!
If they get attacked again, they will collapse!
Kalau sampai kena serangan lagi, mereka bisa musnah!
모두... 젠장...
Everyone... dammit...
Teman-teman... sial...
그란블레이드!
Granblade!
질까보냐! 너 따위에게! 질까보냐!
I'm not losing! No way I'm losing to a scum like you!
Aku akan mengalahkanmu! Aku tidak akan kalah darimu!
브레이크 참!
Break Slash!
글라디온, 데미지 한계!
Gladion is on its damage limit!
Ketahanan Gladion mencapai batasnya!
성장해라. 성장하는 것이다, 글라디온!
Grow up. Grow stronger, Gladion!
Bertahanlah, Gladion. Bertahanlah!
그리고 생각해내라, 웹나이트가 왜 하나뿐이 아닌지. 왜 다 다른 종류인 것인가?
And remember. Why are there more than one Webknights? Why are they all in different types?
Dan ingatlah. Kenapa Webknight tidak hanya satu? Dan kenapa Webknight dibuat dalam berbagai tipe?
잘 알겠지. 인간 따위 지적 생물체에는 무한한 힘 따위는 없다는 것! 자, 이걸로 끝이다!
You understand now, don't you? There is no such thing as unlimited power
Sekarang kalian mengerti, kan? Di dalam tubuh manusia ini,
tidak ada kekuatan yang tidak terbatas! Habislah kalian sekarang!
in a mere intellectual being like humans! Now disappear!
질까보냐!
I won't be defeated!
Aku tidak akan kalah!
뭐?
What?
Apa?
질까보냐! 질까보냐! 질까보냐!
I won't be defeated! I will not be defeated! I won't lose!
Aku tidak akan kalah! Aku tidak akan kalah! Aku tidak akan kalah!!!
yume ni yobare te... nami ni makare te...
글라디온!
Gladion!
우리는 반드시 널 쓰러뜨린다!
We will definitely take you down!
Kami pasti akan mengalahkanmu!
kumo no kirema ni hikari ga mieru
subete shizuka ni shinkashiteiru
글라디온과 피닉스온 프로그램이 링크! 새로운 보안 프로그램으로 성장합니다!
Gladion and Phoenixon program have linked up! They grew up into a new self-defense program!
Program Gladion dan Phoenixon menyatu! Mereka berkembang menjadi program pelindung baru!
omoi de wo tokashinagara
할아버지!
Grandpa!
Kakek!
응, 잘 됐구나!
Yeah, they did it!
Hm. Bagus!
웹체인지! 피닉스온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Phoenixon, Attack Mode!
kanashimi ni tamesare itsudatte hito wa
yami no moufu ni matanige komukeredo
글라디온, 히트 모드!
Gladion, Heat Mode!
합체했군?
They combined?!
Mereka bergabung?!
jidai ni tobikomu yuuki no DIVER
히트 웨이브!
Heat Wave!
ima no kurushimi ya namida wo
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
afureru chikara douka shinjite
해냈다! 해냈어, 글라디온! 드디어 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨렸어!
Yay! We did it, Gladion! We finally took Deletloss down!
Berhasil! Kita berhasil, Gladion! Akhirnya kita berhasil mengalahkan Deletloss!
이 목소리는!
This voice...!
Suara itu...!
데리트로스!
Deletloss!
재미있었군, 웹나이트 놈들.
It was interesting, fellow Webknights.
Menarik juga, para Webknight.
그러나 아쉽군. 네놈들이 방금 쓰러뜨린 건 나의 한 부분에 불과하다.
But, too bad. What you just took down is nothing more than a part of me.
Tapi, sayang sekali. Yang baru kalian kalahkan itu tidaklah lebih dari sebagian kecil dari tubuhku,
데리트로스. 네 목적은 뭔가? 대체 왜 이런 짓을 하나?
Deletloss, what is your true intention? What exactly are you planning?
Apa tujuanmu yang sebenarnya, Deletloss? Apa yang kau rencanakan?
언젠간 알 것이다. 그 때까지 너희들이 살아 있다면 말이지!
You will know soon; if you survive until the time comes, that is!
Kalian akan tahu sendiri, tapi itu kalau kalian masih bisa bertahan hidup sampai saat itu tiba!
데리트로스, 네가 뭘 한다고 해도 난 지지 않는다! 절대로!
Deletloss, whatever trick you use, I will not lose! Never!
Deletloss, biar cara apapun yang akan kau gunakan, aku tidak akan kalah! Itu pasti!
Screenplay
Kubota Masashi
Storyboarding
Staging
Ishiyama Takaaki
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Takeuchi Junko
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Yuuki Natsuko
Kawasaki Eriko
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Sakuraba Kouji
Maekawa Yuuko
Sanjouji Mamoru
Kurokawa Nami
Hara Tsubasa
Itou Miyako
jikuu koete michi e no tobira wo
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Sharkon
Yoshino Hiroyuki
Griffion
Nakamura Yuuichi
Phoenixon
Suzumura Ken'ichi
Deletloss
Tachiki Fumihiko
akete yukeba mirai e no SAIN
aratana kuni hikari ga matataku
bokura ga ima mezashiteru sekai sa
TOGETHER kakemegure
motto doko made mo
kinou made no kimi to wa chigau sou sa
WEBDIVER shinjiyou
kitto bokura ni wa
hontou no ashita ga matteru
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
kanarazu dokoka de
Production
Thank you for watching!
Preview for Next Episode
검은 구름에 사로잡힌 다이버랜드.
Diverland was covered with black shadow.
Diverland diselimuti oleh bayangan hitam kelam.
코스모 에이리어에서 기다리는 거대한 웹나이트.
And a giant Webknight waits in Cosmo Area.
Dan sebuah Webknight raksasa menanti di Cosmo Area.
그 이름은 드라그온.
His name is Dragwon.
Ia bernama Dragwon.
일찍이 없던 강적에 나와 글라디온은 최대의 위기를 맞아.
Having never met such powerful enemy, Gladion and I face our greatest crisis.
Di hadapan musuh yang jauh lebih kuat dari sebelumnya,
aku dan Gladion menghadapi bahaya terbesar kami.
게다가, 드라그온과 함께하는 웹다이버는 나오키였어.
Moreover, the Webdiver who is with Dragwon was that Naoki.
Ditambah lagi, Webdiver yang bersama dengan Dragwon adalah Naoki.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Stay tuned
for the
next story!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !